

Svajune Klimasauskaite

Senior IT Business Analyst | Data Scientist

Personal Info: +41 77 94 765 45, svajune@protonmail.com

Zurich, CH-8002, EU nationality (Lithuanian)

An IT professional with 14 years experience in business analysis and systems design for a variety of industries. In recent years, I have been implementing Al-based applications, and learning about it's potentials and pitfalls.

My main interest is to maximise business value and impact through IT, BI and AI-based solutions. That includ accountabilities like defining a solution vision and roadmap, managing stakeholders, their expectations and product backlog, monitoring solution performance and value, and continually adapting to customer needs and behaviours.

A few of my recent deliverables:

- Led quantitative analysis on the clinical trials's PDFs using NLP to standardise and optimise the documentation cycle required for health authorities submission.
- Segmented customer database according to the Big Five personality traits.

Skillset

Frameworks	Agile (SAFe and Scrum), Holacracy, V-Model, Waterfall
Standards	BABOK, PMBOK, DMBOK, UML, TOGAF, PEP 8
Tools	Confluence, Jira, Tableau, Jupyter Notebook, Enterprise Architect, HP-Quality Center, Git, PyCharm.
Technical skills	SQL, Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Spacy, Gensim, scikit-learn, TensorFlow, ETL, Data Modelling, PySpark
Languages	- Lithuanian (fluent), - English (fluent), - Russian (B1), - German (A1)

Professional Experience

2020.09 - 2021.03 Data Scientist (Contractor)

Roche (PDEx-OI Team) - Zurich, Switzerland

- Developed a logical data model from the global operational DWH to create an E2E dataset of clinical trials activities, resources and costs.
- Applied statistical and machine learning techniques such as **regression**, **dimensionality reduction**, **clustering** and **anomaly detection** on time series data.
- Created a **data extraction pipeline** to convert pharmaceutical PDF documents to JSON format for further analysis.
- Applied various NLP methods to text analysis, such as word embeddings and topic modelling, to understanding structural and contextual document differences.
- Introduced and implemented a collaborative environments such as **GitLab** and **Confluence**, as well as **software engineering principles** for data science code.

2019.01 - 2020.08 Data Scientist (Contractor / Investor)

Early Phase Startups - Zurich, Switzerland

- Designed and implemented a **cost-effective** data dashboards.
- Conducted a customer psychometric observational study in collaboration with ZhaW Zurich University.
- Acquired subjective and objective psychometric data. Objective data captured via EEG, heart rate, skin conductivity and facial expression. Subjective data captured via deep psychological interview.
- Applied speech recognition solution (Speechmatic) to convert the audio signal into a text, for further NLP processing, such as sentiment analysis and topic modelling.
- Consolidated subjective and objective data along with customers payment behaviour. This gave
 us the basis for tailoring marketing campaigns to resonate with specific segment of population.

2017.08 - 2018.12 IT Business Analyst (Contractor)

Credit Suisse (SUB) - Zurich, Switzerland

- Tailored Agile technique for **DWH and BI teams** to find the optimal fit of the methodology within organisational constraints. Achieved **sprint commitment** to 95%.
- Modeled a credit risk data, specified ETL process and defined SQL queries for data retrieval.
- Designed business reports to build valuable insights that enabled the business to act.

2016.11 - 2017.07 IT Business Analyst (Contractor)

UBS (US region) - Barcelona, Spain

- Scaled Email Marketing Campaign solution from PoC to production.
- Planned, organised, communicated, specified software requirements and supported globallydistributed development team.

2016.09 - 2016.10 Camino de Santiago pilgrimage experience

2014.07 - 2016.08 Lead IT Business Analyst (Contractor)

European Intellectual Property (IP) Office - Alicante, Spain

- Facilitated attorneys' work by implementing the Case Law Search solution, which consolidated IP decisions from internal and external sources (i.e. National Court, General Court and Court of Justice) in 24 EU languages.
- Eliminated paper registration forms by **upgrading** the IP-Design efiling **application**.
- Consolidated EU Infringement Cases by implementing ACRIS solution, which served various stakeholders, such as Trade European Commission, EU Delegations, Enforcement authorities and EU businesses.
- Implemented solution to **encompass legal content sites** available in each member states.
- Transformed HR and Finance operations by aligning processes to SAP Success factor, SAP BPC and SAP Concur products.

2010.03 - 2014.06 Lead IT Business Analyst | Product Manager

Baltic Amadeus - Vilnius, Lithuania

- Introduced the upcoming business process changes via as-is and to-be analysis.
- Performed gap analysis and achieved alignment across all involved stakeholders, like sponsors, SMEs, change management, cross-functional teams, PMs, BAs, Architects, QAs and Developers.
- **Successfully launched** new core banking system (Oracle Flexcube) with products that I directly curated such as Direct Debit and Utility Payments, Trade Finance and Factoring.
- Performed an assessment analysis for EUR currency adaptation within Direct Debit and Utility Payment products.
- Improved the business requirements of the tender package by removing ambiguity.
- Performed a cost-benefit analysis for asset maintenance software to determine the best fit for purpose.
- Managed COTS product development and pre-sale activities. Successfully scaled across various industries like Natural Gas, Oil Refinery, Bank, Ministry, University.

2007.03 - 2010.02

IT Business Analyst

Affecto Lietuva - Vilnius, Lithuania

- **Scaled** the centralised document management system from PoC to production across 50 regions.
- **Designed APIs** to integrate with other applications like Pension Fund, Social Allowance, Hospitals, National Archive, etc.
- Implemented a **self-service portal** for the insurer and insured to push social services online.
- Adopted a national, certified digital signature throughout the complete lifecycle of the process.
 i.e. from submission up to archive.
- Refactored the back-end solution from the hierarchical database to a relational database due to technical limitations.
- **Implemented** a Decentralised Claim Administration solution to eliminate fraud cases, optimise administration and distribute the workload throughout different geographical offices.

Education

Continuous Education

MSc in

Electronics Engineering

@ Vilnius Gediminas Technical University, Lithuania. 2006 - 2009

BSc in

Electronics Engineering

Wilnius GediminasTechnical University,Lithuania, 2002 - 2006

- CBAP Business Analysis @IIBA, 2021
- Data Science Nanodegree @Udacity, 2021
- ML with TensorFlow Nanodegree @Udacity, 2020
- **SAFe** Product Owner/Product Manager, 2019
- Al Product Manager Nanodegree @Udacity, 2019
- Data Analyst Nanodegree @Udacity, 2019
- CBIP Data Analysis and Design @TDWI, 2019 (1/3)
- UML Professional Advanced @OMG, 2012